National Institute of Labor Education (NILE) Papers 5545
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Institute of Labor Education (NILE) Papers
1957-1968
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Institute of Labor Education (NILE)
5545
38 cubic feet
38 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Includes materials generated by and about the National Institute of Labor Education's Mental Health Project, regarding union mental health programs and mental health research and education in universities.
2299586
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Andy and Connie, July 14, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The National Institute of Labor Education's Mental Health Project (1959-1966) was directed by Robert Reiff (chief psychologist, Jewish Board of Guardians) and funded by a grant from the National Institute of Mental Health. Its purpose was to study the possible development and implementation of a program of mental health education, training, and research in labor unions.
Scope and Contents
Includes reports, letters, programs of workshops, pamphlets, and memoranda regarding the planning and administration of mental health programs in New Jersey, New York, Maryland, California, Pennsylvania, Michigan, Minnesota, and Missouri; mental health research and education conducted by the universities of Wisconsin, Cincinnati, Connecticut, Minnesota, Puerto Rico, and Columbia University, Cornell University, Pennsylvania State University, and Rutgers University; and mental health programs for the United Automobile Workers, United Rubber Workers, the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, the New York Hotel Trade Council, the Sidney Hillman Health Center of New York, the New York Shipping Association, the International Longshoremen's Association, and the Retail Clerks Psychiatric Clinic.
Also, news releases and bulletins of the National Association of Psychiatric Hospitals, American Medical Association, National Associat1on of State Mental Health Program Directors, the American Psychological Association, the American Psychiatric Association and NILE Mental Health Program. In addition, administrative documents, grant proposals, and proposals for research. Also, position and research papers pertaining to mental health programs for low income groups, collective bargaining issues relating to job security for mentally ill workers, mental health programs relating to labor and low income groups, development of a labor mental health program, mental health and negotiated health and welfare plans, the financing of mental health services and facilities, a rehabilitation project for union members released from psychiatric hospitals, technological unemployment and the human factor, long range planning for psychiatric care, the sociology of occupations and professions, and community workers' education programs.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5234: Inter-University Labor Education Committee Records 5767: National Institute of Labor Education Additional Records 5944: National Institute of Labor Education Additional Records
Community welfare councils; International relations; Mental health planning z California.; Mental health planning z Maryland.; Mental health planning z Michigan.; Mental health planning z Minnesota.; Mental health planning z Missouri.; Mental health planning z New Jersey.; Mental health planning z New York (State); Mental health planning z Pennsylvania.; Mental health education z United States.; Technological unemployment z United States.; Labor union welfare funds z United States.; Agricultural Workers. Education. United States.; Labor and laboring classes. Education. United States.; Labor and laboring classes. Mental health. United States.; Labor and laboring classes. Scholarships, fellowships, etc. United States.; Labor and laboring classes. Southern States. Economic conditions.; Labor and laboring classes. United States. Medical care.; Labor ethics.; Labor history. Study and teaching (Continuing education). United States.; Labor movements. Comparative study.; Preretirement counseling.; Rank and file participation.; Trade-union democracy.; Trade-union leadership. United States.; Trade-unions. United States. Cultural activity.; Trade-unions. United States. Social action.; Trade-unions. United States. Social activity.; Workers' education. Developing countries.; Workers' education. United States. Curricula.; Workers' education. United States.; United States. Race relations.; Adolfson, Lorentz; Anderson, Florence; Barbash, Jack.; Bergmann, Ralph H.; Blakely, Robert J.; Breen, Leonard; Campbell, Ralph N. (Ralph Norton), 1910-; Coit, Eleanor G.; Cole, David L.(David Lawrence), 1902-1978; Conners, John D.; Cook, Alice Hanson; Farley, Robert; Fletcher, C. Scott (Cyril Scott),1904-1991; Galenson, Walter, 1914-1999; Garman, Phillips, L.; Glynn, John; Gottfurcht, Hans, 1896-1982; Graham, Frank Porter, 1886-1972; Gray, Lois S. (Lois Spier), 1923-; Hayes, Albert; Hoehler, Fred K. (Fred Kenneth), 1893-1969; Holland, Kenneth; Kerrison, Irvine L. H. (Irvine Ledward Hamilton), 1916-; Knowles, Malcolm S. (Malcolm Shepherd), 1913-1997; Kornbluh, Hy; Lester, Richard Allen, 1908-1997; Levine, Herbert A.; Leys, Wayne A. R. (Wayne Albert Risser); Luchek, Anthony; McCallister, Frank; McDonald, David J. (David John), 1912-1978; Meany, George, 1894-1980; Meyers, Charles A.; Mire, Joseph; Mitchell, Samuel H.; Moore, David G. (David Graham), 1918-; Neufeld, Maurice F.; Pagano, Jules; Pragan, Otto; Rogin, Lawrence M.; Romualdi, Serafino, 1900- 1967; Schuster, George; Sexton, Brendan; Stern, James L.; Strong, Peter; Uphoff, Walter Henry, 1913-1998; Van Hecke, Maurice Taylor, 1892-1963; Wann, Andrew J.; AFL-CIO; Afro-American Labor Center.; American Federation of Government Employees; American Federation of Teachers; American Federation of Teachers. Workers Education Local 189; American University (Washington, D.C.); Ansonia Manufacturing Company; Austrian Training Program; Canada Labour Congress; Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults; Citizens' Crusade Against Poverty; Colorado Labor Council; University of Colorado; Continuing Committee on Urban Life; Cornell University; Danforth Foundation (Saint Louis, Mo.); Ford Foundation. Fund for Adult Education.; International Association of Machinists; International Chemical Workers Union; International Federation of Workers' Education Associations; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Longshoremen's Association; International Union, United Automobile Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America; Michigan State University; National Institute of Labor Education (U.S.); National Institute of Mental Health (U.S.); National Science Foundation (U.S.); New York Bakery and Confectionery Workers' Apprenticeship Program; New York Hotel Trades Council; New York Shipping Association; Pan American Union; Peace Corps (U.S.); Pennsylvania State University; Pratt & Whitney Aircraft Group; Purdue University; Sidney Hillman Health Center of New York; United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum, and Plastic Workers; United States. Agency for International Development.; United States. International Cooperation Administration.; United States. Office of Economic Opportunity.; United Steelworkers of America; University of California, Berkeley; University of California, Los Angeles; University of Chicago; University of Illinois at Chicago; University of Iowa; University of Massachusetts at Amherst; University of Michigan; University of Wisconsin; Wayne State University
2299586
- A.I.D. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adult Education Association (Box 1, Folder 2)
- AFL-CIO Headquarters (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Labor Service (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Allen, Russell, Education Director of the Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Amalgamated Trust and Savings Bank (Box 1, Folder 6)
- American Institute for Free Labor Development (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Auditor File (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Austrian Training Program (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Automation (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bank, National, D.C. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Board and Executive Committee VII, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Board Members VI, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Board Members V, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Board Members IV, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Board Members III, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Board Members II, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Board Members I, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Breen, Leonard (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Brochure on NILE (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Campbell, Ralph N. I, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Campbell, Ralph N. II., 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Campbell, Ralph N. III., 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Canadian Labour Congress (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Center for the Study of Liberal Education (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Central Office III., 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Central Office II., 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Central Office I. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Scope and Contents
  thru 1958
- Civil Liberties (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Clippings (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Community Participation (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Community Welfare Council (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Comparative Labor Movements (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Conference on Education for Public Responsibilities (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
- Campbell, Ralph N. IV, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Conference Finances, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Conference Reports (Box 3, Folder 3-5)
- Conference Finances, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Connors, John, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Continuing Committee on Urban Life (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Cultural Use of Leisure Time (Box 3, Folder 9)
- D.C.. Withholding Tax (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Economic Education Meeting (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Ethical and Moral Standards (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Evaluation, Residential Study Institutes, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 13-15)
- Extension of Labor Education (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Extension of Labor Education, Standing Committee (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Financial Reports (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Foreign Policy Association, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Friedrich - Ebert - Stiftung (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Fundamental Education, Readership (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Golden, Clint (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Hoehler, Fred (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Humanities (Box 4, Folder 2)
- International Cooperation Administration (ICA) Contract II (Box 4, Folder 3)
- ICA Contract (Box 4, Folder 4)
- ICA Finances (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
- ICA Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 7)
- ICA Overseas Contract (Box 4, Folder 8)
- International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU) (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Individuals I., 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Individuals II., 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Industrial Union Department (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Inquiries about NILE (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Institute of International Education and Fulbright (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Insurance (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Inter-Group Relations (Box 4, Folder 16)
- International Affairs (Box 4, Folder 17)
- International Affairs, Finances (Box 4, Folder 18)
- International Federation of Workers* Educational Associations (Box 4, Folder 19)
- International Labor Organization (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Job Applicants (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Labor's Public Responsibilities i960, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Labor Education, Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
- Latin-American Proposal (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Lectureships on Industrial Relations (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Leys, Wayne A.R. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Membership Participation (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Memos III. 1963- (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Memos II. 196O-I962, 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Memos I. 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Mental Health Continuation Project I., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  January-June 1963
- Mental Health Continuation Project II., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  July-December 1963
- Mental Health Continuation Project II., 1962 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Mental Health Continuation Project I., 1957-1961 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Mental Health i960, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Mental Health I. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Minutes (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Mire, Joseph, Foreign Friends (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Mire, Joseph, Personal Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Non-Labor Agencies II., 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Non-Residential Study Institutes IV., 1963 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Non-Residential Study Institutes III., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  October-December 1962
- Non-Residential Study Institutes II., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Sep-62
- Project Areas, General, 1957-1963 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Non-Residential Study Institutes I., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  January-September 1962
- Northwest Airlines (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Overseas Trip (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Pan American Union (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Payroll, 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 4-9)
- Peace Corps (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Personnel (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Photographs (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Pre-Retirement Education IV., 1963 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Pre-Retirement Education III., 1962 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Pre-Retirement Education II., 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Pre-Retirement Education I., 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Pre-Retirement Finances, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Program Committee (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Public Affairs Pamphlet, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Publicity for NILE (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Reiff, Robert (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Report to the Board (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Residential Study Institutes (R.S.I.) V., 1962 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- R.S.I. IV., 1961 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  June-December 1961
- R.S.I. III., 1961 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  January-May 196l
- R.S.I. II., 1960 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  July-December i960
- R.S.I. I., 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  1959-July I960
- R.S.I. California (Box 8, Folder 5)
- R.S.I. Cornell (Box 8, Folder 6)
- R.S.I. Michigan (Box 8, Folder 7)
- R.S.I. Inquiries, 1960-1962 (Box 8, Folder 8-10)
- R.S.I. Publicity (Box 8, Folder 11)
- R.S.I. Applications (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Rogin, Larry (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Royal McBee, Contract (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Scandinavian Exchange Program (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Selection Committee (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Southern Staff Institute, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Southern Staff Institute, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Southern Staff Institute Applications (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Starr, Emile (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Straus Printing Company, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Taxes (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Teachers' Insurance and Annuity Association (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Technological Change, Task Force, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
- Thermo-Fax Contract (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Unemployment Compensation (Box 9, Folder 8)
- United States ' Departments (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Urbanization, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Urbanization, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- World Affairs Center (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Youth Employment Program, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Youth Employment Program, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  1962-June 1963
- Foundations, General, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Foundations, General I., 1957-1959 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- American Scandinavian (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Carnegie (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Field (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Ford (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Fund for Adult Education II., 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Fund for Adult Education I. i, 1957-1959 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Fund for the Republic (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Hill Family (Box 10, Folder 10)
- New World (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Rockefeller Brothers' Fund, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Rockefeller (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Unions, General (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Auto Workers (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Machinists (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Garment workers (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Steelworkers (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Universities, General I., 1957-1959 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Universities, General II., 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- University of California, Berkeley (Box 10, Folder 21)
- University of California, Los Angeles (Box 10, Folder 22)
- University of Chicago (Box 10, Folder 23)
- University of Colorado (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Columbia University (Box 10, Folder 25)
- University of Connecticut (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Cornell -University (Box 11, Folder 1)
- University of Illinois (Box 11, Folder 2)
- University of Massachusetts (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 11, Folder 4)
- University of Michigan (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Michigan State University (Box 11, Folder 6)
- University of Minnesota (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Ohio State University (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Roosevelt University (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Rutgers University (Box 11, Folder 10)
- University of the West Indies (Box 11, Folder 11)
- University of Wisconsin (Box 11, Folder 12)
- AFL-CIO Headquarters (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Afro-American Labor Center (Box 11, Folder 14)
- A.I.D. (Box 11, Folder 15)
- American Institute for Free Labor Development (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Attorney (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Auditor (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Austrian Training Program (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Board and Executive Committee, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  July-December 1966
- Board and Executive Committee, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  January-June 1966
- Board and Executive Committee, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  July-December 1965
- Board and Executive Committee, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  January-June 1965
- Board and Executive Committee, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  July- December 1965
- D.C. Withholding Tax (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Central Office (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Maryland State Income Tax (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Taxes (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Insurance (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Adult Education Association (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Investments (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Northwest Airlines (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Personnel and Payroll Information (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Teachers' Insurance and Annuity Association (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Unemployment Compensation (Box 12, Folder 11)
- AFL-CIO Headquarters (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Campbell, Ralph N. (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
- Center for Study of Liberal Education (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Citizens Crusade Against Poverty (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Foundations, General (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Carnegie (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Field (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Ford (Box 12, Folder 20)
- New World (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Rockefeller Brothers' Fund, Inc. (Box 12, Folder 22)
- Rockefeller (Box 12, Folder 23)
- Self-Help, Upper Ohio Valley, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  Nov-68
- Stern (Box 12, Folder 25)
- Inventory, NILE (Box 12, Folder 26)
- International Labour Organization (Box 12, Folder 27)
- International Federation of Workers' Educational Associations (Box 12, Folder 28)
- International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (Box 12, Folder 29)
- Inquiries about NILE (Box 12, Folder 30)
- Labor Studies Center (Box 12, Folder 31)
- Labor Education in the United States, Rogin-Rachlin Publicity (Box 12, Folder 32)
- Board and Executive Committee (Box 13, Folder 1)
  January-June 6h
- By Laws (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Campbell, Ralph N. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Canadian Labour Congress (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Central Office (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Clippings (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Community Health Services (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Comparative Labor Movements (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Counselling Programs (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Citizens' Crusade Against Poverty (CAP) (Box 13, Folder 10)
- D.C. Withholding Tax (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Ethics and Moral Standards (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Evaluation, Residential Study Institute (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Extension of Labor Education, Standing Committee (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Films-Labor, Production of (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Finances, Comparative Labor Movements (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Finances, Ethics and Moral Standards (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Financial Reports, NILE (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Finances, Evaluation (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Human Relations Education Project (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Human Relations Education (Box 13, Folder 21)
- ICFTU (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Individuals (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Industrial Union Department (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Inquiries about NILE (Box 13, Folder 25)
- Insurance (Box 13, Folder 26)
- Job Applicants (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Labor Education, Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 28)
- Lease (Box 13, Folder 29-30)
- Leadership Training for Disadvantaged Unionists (Box 13, Folder 31)
- Local 189, American Federation of Teachers (Box 13, Folder 32)
- Maryland State Income Tax (Box 13, Folder 33)
- Memos (Box 13, Folder 34)
- Mental Health Tax Reports (Box 14, Folder 1)
- National Institute for Mental Health (NIMH) Finances II (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Mental Health Project Publications (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Mental Health Project, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Mental Health Project, Finances (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Mental Health Continuation Project V., 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Mental Health Continuation Project III., 1964 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  January-June 1964
- Mental Health Continuation Grant I, Finances (Box 14, Folder 8)
- NIMH, 1963-1964 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- NIMH Tax Reports (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Mire, Joseph (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Minutes of Meetings, Joseph Mires' Notes (Box 14, Folder 12)
- National Science Foundation (Box 14, Folder 13-14)
- Non-Labor Agencies (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Non-Residential Institutes (Box 14, Folder 16-17)
- Northwest Airlines (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Occupational Health (Box 14, Folder 19-20)
- Office of Economic Opportunity (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Personnel (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Photographs (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Pre-Retirement Education (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Pre-Retirement Education, Finances (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Project Areas, General (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Publications (Box 15, Folder 4-7)
- Publicity (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
- Report to the Board (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Residential Study Institutes (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Residential Study Institutes, Finances (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Rogin, Larry (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Southern Staff Institute - Athens, Georgia Applications, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 14-35)
- Southern Staff Institute, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 36)
- Southern Staff Institute, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 37)
- Southern Staff Institute, Applications (Box 15, Folder 38)
- Southern Staff Institute, Finances (Box 15, Folder 39)
- Technological Change, Task Force (Box 15, Folder 40-41)
- Technological Change, Task Force- Papers on Automation (Box 15, Folder 42)
- Technological Change, Task Force- Finances (Box 15, Folder 43)
- Teachers' Insurance and Annuity Association (TIAA) (Box 15, Folder 44)
- Thermo-Fax Contract and Typewriter Contract (Box 15, Folder 45)
- Unemployment Compensation (Box 15, Folder 46)
- Unions, General (Box 15, Folder 47-48)
- United States Departments (Box 15, Folder 49)
- Foundations, General (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Carnegie (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Field (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Ford (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Fund for Adult Education (Box 16, Folder 5)
- New World (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Rockefeller Brothers' Fund, Inc. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Rockefeller (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Stern Family Fund (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Universities, General (Box 16, Folder 10)
- University of California, Berkeley (Box 16, Folder 11)
- University of California, Los Angeles (Box 16, Folder 12)
- University of Chicago (Box 16, Folder 13)
- University of Connecticut (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Cornell University (Box 16, Folder 15)
- University of Illinois (Box 16, Folder 16)
- University of Michigan (Box 16, Folder 17)
- University of Minnesota (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Ohio State University (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Pennsylvania State University (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Roosevelt University (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Rutgers University (Box 16, Folder 22)
- University of Wisconsin (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Urbanization (Box 16, Folder 24)
- Urbanization, Finances (Box 16, Folder 25)
- Youth Employment Program, Progress Report (Box 16, Folder 26)
- Correspondence with Executive Director Joseph Mire (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Executive Director (Box 17, Folder 2)